Jeff Haineault

DevOps/System Engineer



325 China Basin St. #515 San Francisco, CA 94158



jhaineault1@gmail.com 229.263.1540



linkedin.com/in/jeff-haineault portfolio.jeffhaineault.info

6+ years of experience in maintaining complex enterprise environments, delivering excellent customer service to internal clients, and instituting process efficiencies through documentation and training. Trained in Linux system administration, certification for Devops/Cloud administration in progress. Former international touring drummer turned systems engineer.

Experience

Workday

Data Center Systems Engineer

2019 - Present

Monitor network of 4000+ servers and resolve hardware and network issues. Collaborate across global teams and train/mentor engineers.

- Identify and resolve complex server failures using the Linux terminal and Intelligent Platform Management Interfaces.
- Oversee break-fix ticket resolution, improving ticket queue metric by 80%, exceeding company's performance targets.
- Expedited onboarding by establishing documentation of data center processes and procedures.
- Improved stability, performance, and availability by instituting monitoring dashboard system with PowerIQ and WaveFront.

University of Florida

Jr. System Administrator

2017 - 2019

Delivered IT support to 20+ departments across campus.

• Established documentation library to expedite issue resolution and resource onboarding.

Barnes Healthcare Services

IT Technician

2015 - 2017

Provided IT support and onsite network server setup across regional locations.

• Managed user accounts in Active Directory, Office 365, Shoretel, and Citrix.

Valdosta State University

IT Technician

2015 - 2016

Performed troubleshooting for computer, printer, software, and network issues.

 Installed and set-up computer labs and University software on machines throughout campus.

Azalea Health

Software Developer Intern

2015

Provided technical support and maintenance of company database.

• Customized EHR system using PHP, SQL, Javascript, HTML, and CSS.

Technical Skills

System/Networking

 Windows, Linux, Infoblox, Cisco, Citrix

Cloud/Server

 AWS, CentOS 7, Windows Server 2016

Programming

 Python, Bash, Java, HTML, CSS

Virtualization

 Docker, Virtual Machine Manager/KVM, Virtualbox,

Configuration

· Cobbler, Chef

Ticketing & Documentation

Jira, Confluence

Professional Development

Trained in:

- Kubernetes
- · Linux System Administration
- AWS Solution Architecture
- Cloud Infrastructure
- DevOps

Education

BS

Computer Science (2016) Valdosta State University